

Saloni Singh FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

With an entrepreneur mindset, a dreamer and technology lover, will be helping you achieve your goals and grow. Full-stack developer with 2+ years experience in JavaScript, node.js ,express.js and other web technologies . Excellent at developing custom web applications, setting up servers and maintaining them over time. Eager to learn new technologies and apply them in world-class projects. An excellent fit for your established work process and procedures, or will readily advise and help you build proper ones.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality

Indian

Address

Schleißheimer Straße, München, 80797

CONTACT

- inolassingh@gmail.com
- +91-9102090726
- in salonisinghfullstackengg
- inolas05

WORK EXPERIENCE

Design Engineer

SEAGATE TECHNOLGY

January 2016-Feburary 2018

Associated with SSD development department. My responsibilities included: Design, development and maintenance of the SAP UI5 web applications. UI5 related programming like JavaScript, HTML5, CSS. Building internal web portal for tracking and tracing different components of SSD. Modifying source code to enhance stability and to fix defects. Implement feature additions/enhancements to the source code. Plan and implement end-to-end automation tests from the UI, including backend validations.

Full Stack Developer

FREELANCE March 2018-Present

1) Fin-tech Project - Company based out of USA developing banking authentication software. My role was to implement authentication and authorization mechanism for the software. Tools used - JavaScript, Node.js, Postman, Express.js, Git.

2)E-commerce Project - Company based out of USA having multiple brand apparel products whose customer base is USA. My role was to design the inventory and in memory search functionality for the product .Tools used - JavaScript, Node.js, React, CSS flexbox, Git

Freelance

PERSONAL PROJECTS

March 2018-Present

1) Smart-Brain:

(https://github.com/inolas05/Smartbrain)(https://github.com/inolas05/smartbrain_api)

A face recognition app using an Artificial Intelligence API with complete authentication mechanism using Bcrypt. It does detailed logging of artificial intelligence face detection usage by users and has a responsive web design. Tools used: HTML5, CSS Flexbox, React.js, JavaScript, Git, Git BASH, PostgreSQL, Node js, Express js, Postman.

2) Robo-Friends: (https://github.com/inolas05/Robofriends-App)
A real time search app that fetches data from 2 different APIs. It has in- memory search functionality and displays items dynamically based on search criteria. It has a responsive web design. Tools used: HTML5, CSS Flexbox, React.js, JavaScript, Git, Git BASH

EDUCATION

B.Tech (Electronics & Communication Engineering)

MANIPAL ACADEMY OF HIGHER EDUCATION

July 2012-July 2016

Complete Web Developer Course

ZERO TO MASTERY ACADEMY

2021

Data Structures and Algorithm

ZERO TO MASTERY ACADEMY

2021

FRONT END SKILLS

JavaScript HTML/HTML5 Bootstrap React + Redux m+ React Hooks

Responsive Design CSS3 + flexbox ES6

BACKEND SKILLS

Node.js RESTful API PostgresSQL SQL express.js security Authentication

Authorization Postman

CI/CD AND OTHER SKILLS



LANGUAGE



REFERENCE

Uday Kumar

GE Healthcare , Munich
Uday.kumar3@ge.com , +4915166496332